The William Siegmann Collection, 1932-2007 IULC038 IULC038
Liberian Collections
- Projects
  - Aesthetics of Power: African Art Along the Windward Coast
    - Private Collections
      - Spencer, Titian, undated
      - Spiegl, Jacqueline, undated
      - Spitz, Jolanda, undated
      - Stanley, C. Maxwell, undated
      - Stanoff Collection, undated
      - Steffens, Pete, undated
      - Stolper Collection, undated
      - Storrer, E., undated
      - Suggs, Alexander, undated
      - Tagialferri, Aldo, 1980
      - Tara Collection, undated
      - Taylor, L. Kenneth, 1977-1979
      - Taylor, William, undated
      - Tibbet, John, undated
      - Tishman Collection, undated
      - Traore, Mamode, undated
      - Trombetta Collection, undated
      - Tschappat Collection, undated
      - Tulk, Alfred James, 1983
      - Tursch, Ben, undated
      - Underwood Collection, undated
      - Van Bussel, L., undated
      - Van Den Abbeele Collection, undated
      - Vander Straete, Joesph, undated
      - Verheyleweghen Collection, undated
      - Verite, Pierre, undated
      - Vertes, L, undated
      - Votan, Albert, undated
      - Vraneken Collection, undated, 1980
      - Wallace, Leon, 1979
      - Wagastaff, Samuel, undated
      - Wells, Louis, undated
      - Weston, Robert, undated
      - Wetzel, Nancy Mayer, 1980-1982
      - White Collection, undated
      - White, Kat, undated
      - Whitehouse, Leonard, undated
      - Wilcox, Philip, undated
      - Wilke, Ulfert, undated
      - Winizki, Ernst,, undated, 1980
      - Wilz, Paul, undated
      - Withofs Collection, undated
      - Woelffer Collection, undated
      - Wolf, Ben, undated
      - Wolf, H., undated
      - Wolff, Nigel, undated
      - Wrubel, Tom, undated
      - Wurtzburger, Alan, undated
      - Wyss Collection, undated
      - Zimmer, M.,, undated, 1980
      - Zongo, Issaka, undated
      - Zurcher, Victor, undated
    - Subject Files
      - Aesthetics of Power Catalogue, undated
      - African Carvings, undated
      - Africans Dealing in African Art, undated, 1980
      - Antiquities Law, undated
      - Bolays of Bolahun Film,, undated, 1983-1986
      - Consultants Meetings, undated, 1980
      - Dan Figures, undated
      - Exhibition Proposal, 1981
      - Films and Slides, undated, 1979-1982
      - Foreet Sacre, 1982
      - Friends of Ethnic Art, 1982
      - Grant Proposal Guidelines, undated, 1978-1979
      - The Harley Masks of Northeast Liberia, 1977
      - Implementation Budget, undated, 1980-1982
      - Implementation Proposal Mailing, undated
      - Kissi Stone Figures, undated
      - Kono Art, undated
      - Koronko Art, undated
      - Kpelle Masks, undated
      - Liberia Trip,, undated, 1983
      - Liberian Embassy, 1980
      - Liberian Masks - Formal Anaylsis and Style Regions, undated
      - List of Collections/Collectors in Britain,, undated, 1980
      - Loma Art, undated
      - Makona River, undated
      - Meetings - Tom and Bill, undated, 1980-1982
      - Miscellaneous, undated, 1979-1981
      - Miscellaneous Art, undated
      - Miscellaneous Liberian Government Documents, 1980-1982
      - Musical Instruments in Context, undated
      - Naming of Masks, undated
      - NEH The Bolays of Bolahun Film,, undated, 1982-1983
      - NEH Correspondence,, undated, 1978-1980
      - NEH Film Project Proposal,, undated, 1989-1983
      - NEH Implementation Proposal,, undated, 1981-1982
      - NEH Planning Grants,, undated, 1978-1981
      - NEH Planning Grants Budget, 1979-1981
      - Nile to Mano Migration: Speculations on the Historical Geography of the Mande Language, undated
      - Peabody Museum/Harvard University,, undated, 1932-1940
      - Prospectus, undated, 1980-1981
      - Sculptors and Sculptures of the Dan, 1962
      - Smithsonian Letter of Recommendation, 1984
      - Sothebys (London), undated
      - Sothebys (New York), undated
      - Studio Museum (Harlem), 1982
      - USSR- Soviet Museums, undated
      - West African Secret Societies - Maps, undated
      - Windward Coast Bibliography, undated
      - Windward Coast Masks, undated
  - Art of the Cavalla River
    - Bibliography Collecton Forms, undated, 1992-1994
    - Images, 1981
    - Miscellaneous, undated
    - Miscellaneous Forms, undated
    - Object Selection List, undated
    - Picture File Collection Forms, undated, 1990-1993
    - Sample Objects, undated
  - Brooklyn Museum
    - Accesion Records, undated
    - Acquisitions Committee Meetings, undated
    - African Gallery Floor Plans, undated
    - African Gallery Guides, undated
    - African Gallery Notes, 1986-1987
    - African Gallery Permanent Installation, undated, 1972-1976
    - African Gallery Permanent Installation - Gathering Materials, undated, 1970-1976
    - Amherst College,, undated, 1992
    - Amonikoyi, Ali, undated
    - Annual Reports/Installation 1904-1938, undated
    - Art Object Checklist Collection Forms for "Art of the Guinea Coast", 2003-2004
    - Art of Black Africa (Dan Culture), 1993
    - Archives of Traditional Music - Indiana University
    - Brooklyn Collects,, undated, 2000-2001
    - Bryn Mawr African Collection,, undated, 1993-1995
    - Christie's Auction, 1995
    - Correspondence, 1992-2004
    - "Curator's Choice" Exhibit,, undated, 1986
    - Dan Brass Stilt Dancers, 1993
    - Deinstalled Art from the African Gallery, undated, 1989
    - Detroit Institute of Arts,, undated, 1996
    - Everhart Museum Figures, undated
    - Hamill Gallery of African Art, 1993-2006
    - "Kongo: Echoes of an Ancient Kingdom" Exhibit, 1982-1983
    - L. Kahan Gallery, Inc,, undated, 1992
    - Labels, 1989
    - Ldamie: Figurative Brass Caster of the Dan, 1985
    - Leipzig,, undated, 1994
    - Mancala, undated, 1991
    - Maps of Africa, undated
    - Masks from the Joss Collection - UCLA,, undated, 1992-1993
    - "Mask Visions" Exhibit,, undated, 1978
    - Memorial Art Gallery, 1995-1996
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1987-2004
    - Metropolitan Museum of Modern Art, 1992
    - Musee d'Ethnographie, Neuchatel,, undated, 1989-1991
    - Museum fur Volkerkunde (Vienna),, undated, 1994
    - Museum Management, 1984-1992
    - NEA Grant Application, 1989
    - National Museum of Abidjan, undated
    - National Museum of African Art, 1990-1999
    - National Museum of Liberia,, undated, 1987-1994
    - Neprajzi Muzeum,, undated, 1994
    - North Carolina Museum of Art,, undated, 1998-2003
    - Peabody Museum, 2003
    - Plans and Preliminary Drafts for 1995 Exhibition,, undated, 1994
    - Primative Negro Arts Prints, undated, 2005
    - Proposed Gifts, undated, 1986-1997
    - Rautenstrauch Joest Museum, 1989
    - Reinstallation Checklist, undated, 1989
    - Rietberg Museum, undated
    - Seabrook, William Buehler,, undated, 1992-1993
    - Smithsonian Correspondence, 1992
    - Toma Headdress, 2000-2001
    - UCLA Collection Notes, undated
    - Yoruba Exhibit, undated
  - Louisiana World Expo
    - Budgets and Receipts, undated, 1983-1984
    - Correspondence, undated, 1983-1987
    - Floor Plans, undated, 1983-1984
    - Invitations and Programs, 1984
    - Labels, undated
    - Liberian Pavilion, undated
    - Loan Agreements, undated, 1984
    - "Traditional Arts of Liberia", 1984
  - SMA Fathers
    - Appraisal and Donation List undated, 1980-1982
    - Correspondence, 1978-1983
    - Ethiopian Paintings, undated
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1979-1982
    - Musee Africain (Lyon),, undated, 1979
    - Newsletters, 1981-1983
    - Scanlon Catalog, undated
    - Sculptures, undated
    - Yoruba Presentation Bowl, undated, 1980
  - Subject Files
    - Africana Museum Annual Report, 1969-1975
    - African Dress and Textile Arts Symposium, undated, 1980-1982
    - African Material Culture Conference, undated, 1986
    - Agricultural Communications Circuit, 1980
    - Appraisal, 1982
    - Art Collections For Sale, undated
    - Artifacts Sheets, undated
    - Babbhbli Brass Casters, undated
    - Belewale Brass, undated
    - Benin Plaque, undated
    - Berg-en-dal Style, undated
    - Brass Figures - Cuttington Style, undated, 1986
    - Brass Figures - Ldamie Style, undated
    - Brass Figures - Winizki Style, undated
    - Correspondence, 1983
    - Cuttington Museum Inventory and Catalog,, undated, 1991
    - d'Azevedo Correspondence, 1971-1972
    - Denwar Ceramics, 1974
    - Depositors' Receipts, 1981
    - Eiteljorg Catalogue,, undated, 1980-1982
    - Gbi-Doru Chiefdom, undated
    - Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco Code of Ethics,, undated, 1982
    - Friends of Ethnic Art, 1982
    - "Folklore in Africa Today" Colloquium, 1984
    - Gameboards - Animal Heads, undated
    - Gameboards - Cups On End, undated
    - Gameboards - Slides, undated
    - Gameboards - Human Heads, undated
    - Gameboards - Mano River, undated
    - Girls Initiation Among the Mende Exhibit, 1979
    - Himmelheber, Hans, undated
    - Hollas Collection - Paris, undated
    - In the Yacouba Country, undated
    - IBM, 1984
    - Institut Africain International,, undated, 1982-1983
    - Lamp, Fred,, undated, 1979-1983
    - Liberian Museums, undated, 1982-1983
    - Library of Congress Order Forms, undated
    - Loans to the Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco AOA,, undated, 1971-1979
    - Mancala, undated, 1984
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1984
    - Museum Registration Forms, undated
    - NEH Grants, 1986
    - National Geographic Magazine, 1982
    - National Museum of Liberia,, undated, 1994-2007
    - New Orleans Museum of Art,, undated, 1977-1987
    - Panoramic Dream: Antwerp and the World Exhibitions, 1997
    - Pa Weaver - Freetown Archives, undated
    - Peabody Museum,, undated, 1977-1988
    - Proposal for Archaeological Investigation, undated
    - Ravenhill, Philip, 1980-1984
    - Seattle Art Museum - White Collection, 1984
    - Sieber, Roy, 1977-1999
    - Siegmann's Tenure at Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco, 1978-1981
    - Slide Duplication, 1980
    - Travel Info, undated, 1980-1981
    - Triennial Symposium on African Art, 1980
    - Treasures of Ancient Nigeria Exhibit, 1980
    - University of Iowa Symposium of African Art,, undated, 1981-1982
- Research
  - Art (Box 10)
    - "Accumulation: Power and Display in African Sculpture"; Arnold Rubin, 1993 (Box 10)
    - "African Aesthetics"The Carlon Monzini Collection"; Susan Mullin Vogel, 1986 (Box 10)
    - "African Art at the Cincinnati Art Museum"; Sigrid Docken Mount, 1980 (Box 10)
    - "African Art for Children"; Lois Gordon, undated (Box 10)
    - "'African Art of the West Atlantic Coast': Some Annotations and Sundry Matters", undated (Box 10)
    - "The African Art Market"; Hersey Irwin, 1982 (Box 10)
    - "African Arts"; Pascal Imperato, 1976 (Box 10)
    - "African Fabric Arts: Sources of African Design and Technique"; Esther Warner Dendel, 1974 (Box 10)
    - "African Mancala"; Smithsonian National Museum of Art, undated (Box 10)
    - "African 'Primitives': Function and Form in African Masks & Figures"; G. W. Sannes, 1970 (Box 10)
    - "African Sculpture: The Shape of Surprise"; Susan Mullin Vogel, 1979 (Box 10)
    - "African Treasures of the Peabody Museum, Harvard"; Monni Adams, undated (Box 10)
    - "Africa's Contempory Art and Artists - Liberia"; Evelyn S. Brown, 1966 (Box 10)
    - "Aluminum Pot Casting Technique"; Thomas Seligman, 1981 (Box 10)
    - "Ambiguous Sexuality of Isoko Deities: Androgyny of Asexuality?"; Philip M. Peek, 1989 (Box 10)
    - "The Amulet-Laden Tunics of Hunters, Political Leaders and Warriors in West Africa"; Ruth M. Stone, 1973 (Box 10)
    - "Ancient Wood Figures from Sierra Leone: Implications for Historical Reconstruction"; Frederick Lamp, undated (Box 10)
    - "An Appraisal of the African Art and Artifact Collection of Warren and Kathy D'Azavedo"; Jerome Evans, 2003 (Box 10)
    - "Art and Handicraft in North-Eastern Liberia"; Etta Dunner, 1939 (Box 10)
    - "Art and History in Ghana"; Roy Sieber, 1967 (Box 10)
    - "Art and Politics: A Staff from the Court of Benin, West Africa"; Susan Mullin Vogel, 1979 (Box 10)
    - "'ART/Artifact': On the Museum and Anthropology"; James C. Faris, 1988 (Box 10)
    - "Art as an Element of Culture in Africa: Ethnographical Material"; A.A. Gerbrands, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Art Exhibits and Brochures, 1978-2000 (Box 10)
    - "Art Historical Research in Africa"; Roy Sieber, 1989 (Box 10)
    - "The Art Historian as Conceptual Analyst"; Barry Hallen, 1979 (Box 10)
    - "Art, History, and Art History"; Daniel McCall, 1971 (Box 10)
    - "Art in Africa"; Tibor Bodrogi, 1969 (Box 10)
    - "Art in Ancient Africa"; William Bascom, 1941 (Box 10)
    - "Art in Liberia", undated (Box 10)
    - "Artists in Liberia and The United States: A Comparitive View"; Karen L. Field, 1981 (Box 10)
    - "Artists of the Dan"; Hans Himmelheber, 1963-1970 (Box 10)
    - "The Art of Liberia"; Thomas Seligman, 1981 (Box 10)
    - "The Art of Senegal in the Corpus of West African Art"; Lou Ann Lamberth, 1971 (Box 10)
    - "The Art of the Dan"; Eberhard Fischer & Hans Himmelheber, 1976 (Box 10)
    - "Art of the Negores" ( 1919 ); Vladimir Ivanovich Matvey, 1996 (Box 10)
    - "The Art of Weaving Country Cloth"; Henry R. Kollie, 1974 (Box 10)
    - "The Arts" Manuscript; William Bascom, undated (Box 10)
    - "Art Versus Collectibles: Why Museums Should be Filled with Fakes"; Edward C. Banfield, 1982 (Box 10)
    - "Assuming the Guise: Williams College Display of African Masks Reveals Powerful Cultural Ties"; Martin Moynihan, 1992 (Box 10)
    - "The Ayobo Mask/Headdress"; Joseph Cornelius Pellegrin, 1975 (Box 10)
    - "Bambara Sculpture from the Wesern Sudan with an Introduction by Robert Goldwater"; Robert Goldwater, 1960 (Box 10)
    - "Bamenda Museum Plans"; Roy Sieber, 1970 (Box 10)
    - "The Bassa Mask - A Stranger in the House"; Roger Dorsinville & Mario Meneghini, 1973 (Box 10)
    - "Benin Bronze Masks: Styles & Chronology"; Philip J.C. Dark, undated (Box 10)
    - "Bete Art"; Christopher D. Roy, 1969 (Box 10)
    - "Beautiful and Grotesque: A Study of Preference Patterns in Ogiriga-Okpella"; Jean M. Borgatti, 1980 (Box 10)
    - "Black African Art as Cosmic Liturgy and Religious Language"; Mveng Engelbert, 1977 (Box 10)
    - "The Bronze Statuettes of Ro-Ponka, Kafu Bulom"; U.H. Koroma, 1939 (Box 10)
    - "The Buli Master, and Other Hands"; Susan Mullin Vogel, 1980 (Box 10)
    - "Bundu Helmet Mask"; Karin McGhee, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Carroll, Fr. Kevin Articles, undated (Box 10)
    - "A Central Ivory Coast Bronze Helment Mask"; Philip L. Ravenhill, 1983 (Box 10)
    - "CHOKWE! Art and Intitiation Among Chokwe and Related Peoples" Grant Proposal; Manuel A. Jordan, 1998 (Box 10)
    - "Collaboration in Ethnographic Film Making"; Timothy Asch, 1988 (Box 10)
    - "Collecting African Art - Guinea and Sierra Leone"; Werner Gillon Rizzoli, 1979 (Box 10)
    - "Collecting - Out of Africa"; Charles Duncan Miller; Interviewed by Leighton H. Coleman, 1997 (Box 10)
    - "The Concave Face in African Art"; Hans Himmelheber, 1971 (Box 10)
    - "The Conservation of Two Mounted Pearl Shells from New Guinea", undated (Box 10)
    - "The Contemporary Nigerian Artist: His Patrons, His Audience, and His Critics";; Michael Crowder, 1978 (Box 10)
    - "Counterfeiting and Other Deviations from Traditional Art in Black Africa"; Hans Himmelheber, 1967 (Box 10)
    - "Craftsmen: Their Continuing Tradition"; Museum of African Art, undated (Box 10)
    - "The Creative Heritage of Africa: An Introduction to African Art"; Encyclopaedia Britannica Education Corporation, 1972 (Box 10)
    - "Creativity and Style in African Art"; William Bascom, 1962 (Box 10)
    - "Criteria Which Determine the Monetary Value of African Art"; Museum of African Art, undated (Box 10)
    - "Cut and Drawn: Thextile Work from Nigeria"; Joanne Ericher, 1982 (Box 10)
    - "The Dance, Art and Rituals of Africa" ' Michel Huet, 1978 (Box 10)
    - "Dan Forest Spirits: Masks in Dan Villages"; Eberhard Fischer, 1978 (Box 10)
    - "The Dan - Habitat and Society"; Eberhard Fischer, 1976 (Box 10)
    - "Dan Masking Style"; Michael J. Hohl, 1982 (Box 10)
    - '"Dan Masks and the Forces of Balance";; Robert Farris Thompson, 1974 (Box 10)
    - "Dan-We Art of Southeastern Liberia and Western Ivory Coast"; Judith Perani & Fred T. Smith, 1998 (Box 10)
    - "Depiction of Facial Paralysis on an African Mask"; Christopher Steiner & Rif S. El-Mallakh, 1987 (Box 11)
    - "Descriptions of Masks"; Esther Dagan, 1992 (Box 11)
    - "Dictionary of Art - 'Dan'"; Eberhard Fischer, undated (Box 11)
    - "Dictionary of Art - 'Kissi'"; Denise Paulme (Box 11)
    - "Dictionary of Art - 'Mende'; Ruth Phillips, undated (Box 11)
    - "Dida Woven Raffia Cloth from Cote d'Ivoire"; Monni Adams & Rose Holdcraft, undated (Box 11)
    - "Does Export Art Belong in Our Art Museums?"; Barbara Johnson, 1982 (Box 11)
    - "Dynamics of Persistence and Change in Akan Aesthetics"; Dennis Warren & J. Kweku Andrews, 1980 (Box 11)
    - "The Elephant in the Art of the Ivory Coast"; Eberhard Fischer, 1983 (Box 11)
    - "Encyclopedia of World Art - 'Liberia'"; Ernesta Cerullli, 1964 (Box 11)
    - "Evolutions in Exhibition Catalogues of African Art"; Sigrid Docken Mount, 1988 (Box 11)
    - "An Examination of the So-Called 'Olokun' Head of Ife, Nigeria"; William Fagg & Leon Underwood, 1949 (Box 11)
    - "Exhibition of Female (Sande) Initiation Masks"; James Willis Gallery, 1974 (Box 11)
    - "The Fagalde Collection of West African Tribal Art", 2005 (Box 11)
    - "Fakes and Forgeries"; Roy Sieber, 1984 (Box 11)
    - "The Fetish that Knew Too Much"; Margaret Plass, 1964 (Box 11)
    - "Fierce or Ugly?"; Roy Sieber, 1985 (Box 11)
    - "Fighting Fire with Fire: The Mandinka Sengko Mask"; Peter M. Weil, 1988 (Box 11)
    - "The Flash of the Spirit: Haiti's Africanizing Vodun Art"; Robert Farris Thompson, undated (Box 11)
    - "Formal Public Titles fo We/Guere Women, Cote d'Ivoire"; Monni Adams, 1991 (Box 11)
    - "Four Dan Sculptors"; Barbara C. Johnson, 1986-1998 (Box 11)
    - Freer Gallery of Art, Smithsonian Institution, undated (Box 11)
    - Ghana: An Exhibition of Contemporary Ghanaian Art, 1982 (Box 11)
    - "The Ghana Door/Mali: A Study of its Origin"; Jack Whitlock, undated (Box 11)
    - "The Grandfather (Mini) Chair of the Guere"; Hans Himmelheber, 1965 (Box 11)
    - "The Great Bieri"; Robert Goldwater, 1962 (Box 11)
    - "The Grebo Mask"; Mario Meneghini, undated (Box 11)
    - "Greek Art"; Detroit Institute of Art, 1973 (Box 11)
    - "Greenwald Collection", 1986 (Box 11)
    - "Guennol: Reflections on Collecting"; Alistair B. Martin, 2003 (Box 11)
    - "The Harley Masks of Mortheast Liberia"; Frederick Lamp, 1975 (Box 11)
    - "The Heart-Shaped Face in African Art"; Edna G. Bay, undated (Box 11)
    - "History of the Brass-Caster"; Eberhard Fischer, 1985 (Box 11)
    - "The Hornbill in Senufo Sculpture"; Daniel F. McCall, 1971 (Box 11)
    - "House of Stones: Memorial Art of Fifteenth-Century Sierra Leone"; Frederick Lamp, 1983 (Box 11)
    - "The Iconography of the Mende Sowei Mask"; Ruth B. Phillips, 1980 (Box 11)
    - "Images of Transcendence in African Art"; J. Weldon Smith, undated (Box 11)
    - "In Search of Identity"; James Lampley, 1978 (Box 11)
    - "The Integration of Animism and Islam in a Mask from Northeast Liberia"; Thomas K. Seligman, 1980 (Box 11)
    - "Interpreting African Masks: The Harley Collection at the Peabody Museum"; Christopher Steiner, 1986 (Box 11)
    - "Italian Art"; Detroit Institute of Art, 1973 (Box 11)
    - "The John B. Henry Collection"; Francine Farr, 2002 (Box 11)
    - "Kereka Blankets of the Peul"; Pascal J. Imperato, 1976 (Box 11)
    - "Knowing the Unknown: The George Way Harley Memorial Collection of Liberian Masks & Artifacts in the Duke University Museum of Art"; Katherine E.M. & Gerald W. Hartwig, 1978 (Box 11)
    - "The Legendery Ancestor Tradition in West African Art"; Douglas Fraser, 1974 (Box 11)
    - "Liberian Art"; Cecily Delafield, 1968 (Box 11)
    - "Liberian Art: A Documentation for a Cultural Heritage for the Liberian People"; Ladislas Segy, undated (Box 11)
    - "Liberian Brass Casting: Nama Blacksmiths", undated (Box 11)
    - "Limba Funeral Masks"; W.A. Hart, undated (Box 11)
    - "The Lower Niger Bronze Industry: Preliminary Analysis and Observations"; Phil Peek, 1969 (Box 11)
    - "Luba Leadership Arts and the Politics of Prestige"; Mary H. Nooter, 1984 (Box 11)
    - "Masking Traditions and Figurative Art Among the Islamized Mende"; Rene Braumann, undated (Box 11)
    - "Masks and Figurines of the Liberian Hinterland"; Roger Dorsinville, 1969 (Box 11)
    - "Masks as Agents of Social Control"; Roy Sieber, 1968 (Box 11)
    - "Masks in the Dan Area of Cote d'Ivoir"; Marie-Noel Verger-Fevre, 1992 (Box 11)
    - "The Masks of the Guere Within the Art of the Upper Cavalla-River Region"; Hans Himmelheber, 1963 (Box 11)
    - "The Masks of Liberia"; Charles Bordogna, 1988 (Box 11)
    - "Mask (Tanka Gle)"; Daniel Reed, undated (Box 11)
    - "Masks - Their Meaning and Their Function"; Andres Lommel, 1972 (Box 11)
    - "Masques de l'Ouest Ivoirien"; Angele Gnonsoa, 1983 (Box 11)
      French and English Translations
    - "The McClain Decision: A New Legal Wrinkle for Museums"; James R. McAlee, 1979 (Box 11)
    - "Miniature Masks from West Africa"; Aldo Tagliaferri, undated (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Art undated, 1982 (Box 11)
    - "Moisi, A Mende Sculptor"; William L. Hommel, undated (Box 11)
    - National Portrait Gallery Posters, 1978-1980 (Box 11)
    - "A Necklace of Glass Beads From West Africa"; C.H. Read, 1905 (Box 11)
    - "The Nomoli of Mende Country"; Stanley Brown, undated (Box 11)
    - "Notes on Bundu Masks"; David Lancy, 1968 (Box 11)
    - "A Note on Guro Statues"; Leon Siroto, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Notes on Gallery Brigitta Hauser, 1988 (Box 11)
    - "Notes on the Poro"; George Harley, undated (Box 11)
    - "The Oliphant in the Musée Caluet at Avignon", 1994 (Box 11)
    - "Out of Africa"; Charles Duncan III & Leighton H. Coleman III, 1997 (Box 11)
    - "Patronage and Change in Nigerian Art"; dele jegede, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Peabody Museum Papers, Schwab & Harley (Box 11)
    - "People of Wood: Baule Figure Sculpture"; Susan Mullin Vogel, 1973 (Box 11)
    - "The Performance of African Art in Africa and in the West"; Simon Ottenberg, undated (Box 11)
    - "Personality and Technique of African Sculptors"; Hans Himmelheber, 1963 (Box 11)
    - "Plastic Arts of Liberian Hinterland"; Liberian Department of Information and Cultural Affairs, 1969 (Box 11)
    - "Preparation of a Large Exhibition"; Barbara Johnson, 1982 (Box 11)
    - "The Present Status of Sculptural Art Among the Tribes of the Ivory Coast"; Hans Himmelheber, 1966 (Box 11)
    - "Problems of Creativity Among the Dan Artists"; Eberhard Fischer, 1976 (Box 11)
    - "Problems of the Diffusion of Mask Styles From the Dan-Ngere Complex"; Ronald G. Atwood, undated (Box 11)
    - Proposal: "Metaphor and Magie: A Study of Carved and Painted Objects from the Trobriand Islands, Through Examination of Museum Collections and Fieldword in the Trobriand Islands"; Kathleen Berrin, 1982 (Box 11)
    - "Pygmy Drawings"; Lynda Einfeld Gallery, 1980 (Box 11)
    - "Rank, Gender, Cult Affiliation Proclaimed in the Arts of Apparel: Reflections on Esie Sculpture"; Daniel McCall, 1984 (Box 11)
    - "Reflections of African Ancestry" Exhibition Poster (Box 11)
    - "Relationships Between African Tribal Art and Modern Western Art"; Max Alfert, 1972 (Box 11)
    - "Report on the Discovery of Clay Pots and Other Relics at Mehnkolo, Grand Cape Mount County, Liberia"; Reginald Townsend, 1966 (Box 11)
    - "Report on the Musee d'Art Africain de Dakar-I.F.A.N."; Philip L. Ravenhill, 1986 (Box 11)